<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>C on ~/Adi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/c/</link>
    <description>Recent content in C on ~/Adi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/c/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Claude Code Tips for SWE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/claude-code-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/claude-code-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been been using Claude Code a lot the past 2 weeks, enough that I hit the Max plan rate limits 3-4x daily.&#xA;These tips have been the biggest quality of life improvement for me. You can find more in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anthropic.com/engineering/claude-code-best-practices&#34;&gt;Anthropic&amp;rsquo;s best practices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Whenever it goes down a wrong path, interrupt immediately and add a memory for the correct action, then tell it to proceed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Compact early, often, and with instructions for what to do next.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you accidentally close it, or want to resume a session, use &lt;code&gt;claude -c&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;/terminal-setup&lt;/code&gt; for shift+enter to insert newlines.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;/config&lt;/code&gt; and set the theme to match your terminal. Makes reading diffs much easier.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tune the allowed tools to minimise the permission prompts, but don&amp;rsquo;t allow destructive commands or unrestricted web interaction&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use it as a shell assistant - it can run any shell command, so it can perform complex workflows like &amp;ldquo;SSH to the server, connect to the database, run a query to find something that points to a file, and download that file&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sonnet requires more steering than Opus. Opus tends to self correct, but Sonnet + more steering can move much faster for simpler tasks. Be mindful of when you&amp;rsquo;ve passed the 50% limit and switches, and switch your style.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Leverage Claude&amp;rsquo;s understanding of &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;gh&lt;/code&gt; to interact with it as co-worker: commit code often, push PRs, address review comments. The Github app makes this the easiest but needs API credits, so using Claude Code to read and interact with Github is a decent workaround.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put effort into your global and project &lt;code&gt;Claude.md&lt;/code&gt;. For monorepos, write one for each directory. Iterate them often. Run them through Anthropic&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anthropic.com/news/prompt-improver&#34;&gt;prompt improver&lt;/a&gt; regularly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/remote-control-claude-code&#34;&gt;Setup a remote shell from your phone to where you run Claude Code&lt;/a&gt;. For certain tasks, it just needs a bit of steering or permission every few minutes, and you need to live your AFK life!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote controlling Claude Code</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p/remote-control-claude-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/remote-control-claude-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/cc-remote.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Remote operating Claude Code from my phone&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anthropic.com/claude-code&#34;&gt;Claude Code&lt;/a&gt; amazed me at launch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Claude 4 release, it cosplays AGI for code &amp;amp; sysadmin tasks, and convinced me to give Anthropic $100/mo.&#xA;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anthropic.com/engineering/claude-code-best-practices&#34;&gt;good advice&lt;/a&gt; about how to get the most out of it so I won&amp;rsquo;t cover that - this is about how to remote operate it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#why&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;  Why&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CC is my &lt;a href=&#34;https://simonwillison.net/2024/Sep/10/software-misadventures/#the-weird-intern&#34;&gt;weird intern&lt;/a&gt; in a terminal, parked on my second screen.&#xA;I mostly keep an eye on it as it works, waiting to respond to permission prompt or steer when I see it going down the wrong path.&#xA;With a good plan (don&amp;rsquo;t outsource your thinking!), &lt;code&gt;Claude.md&lt;/code&gt; (don&amp;rsquo;t outsource your opinions!), it can chip away at a task for hours, but needs steering and approvals.&#xA;Headless mode is fine for simple/self-contained tasks, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adstastic/claude-code-whatsapp-approval&#34;&gt;I built a thing&lt;/a&gt; that lets it Whatsapp me for permission, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for interactive mode.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
