<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Re-Read on ~/adi</title>
    <link>https://adstastic.github.io/tags/re-read/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Re-Read on ~/adi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://adstastic.github.io/tags/re-read/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Remarks on AI From NZ</title>
      <link>https://adstastic.github.io/q/remarks-on-ai-from-nz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adstastic.github.io/q/remarks-on-ai-from-nz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quoting &lt;a href=&#34;https://nealstephenson.substack.com/p/remarks-on-ai-from-nz&#34;&gt;Neal Stephenson&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-humans-can-coexist-with-other-intelligences&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#how-humans-can-coexist-with-other-intelligences&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;  How humans can coexist with other intelligences&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maybe a useful way to think about what it would be like to coexist in a world that includes intelligences that aren’t human is to consider the fact that we’ve been doing exactly that for long as we’ve existed, because we live among animals. Animals have intelligences of many different kinds. We’re used to thinking of them as being less intelligent than we are, and that’s usually not wrong, but &lt;strong&gt;it might be better to think of them as having different sorts of intelligence, because they’ve evolved to do different things&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Be More Agentic</title>
      <link>https://adstastic.github.io/q/how-to-be-more-agentic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adstastic.github.io/q/how-to-be-more-agentic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quoting &lt;a href=&#34;https://usefulfictions.substack.com/p/how-to-be-more-agentic&#34;&gt;Cate Hall&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;radical agency is about finding real edges: things you are willing to do that others aren’t, often because they’re annoying or unpleasant. These don’t always surface in awareness to the point one is actually &lt;em&gt;choosing&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; often they live in a cloud of aversion that strategically obscures the tradeoff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re only asking for things you get, you’re not aiming high enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t trying to get real feedback from people who know you, you’re cooking without tasting. This is, like, the lowest hanging fruit for self-improvement, but few people really try to pick it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pursuing Agency and Reinvention in My 30&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://adstastic.github.io/q/pursuing-agency-and-reinvention-in-my-30-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adstastic.github.io/q/pursuing-agency-and-reinvention-in-my-30-s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quoting &lt;a href=&#34;https://pursuingagency.substack.com/p/pursuing-agency-and-reinvention&#34;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m 34 years old. About the age where you can no longer hide behind the fact that you have plenty of time to grow up and become the person you want to be. It&amp;rsquo;s also not so far into middle age that your efforts in changing can&amp;rsquo;t take root and produce fruit. At least, that&amp;rsquo;s the hope that drives me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I now think of myself as an underachiever. After dozens and, more likely, hundreds of attempts at changing my path, I feel stuck. I&amp;rsquo;ve lost confidence in myself and feel more restless than ever. A change must happen soon, or I worry my personality will be warped permanently by frustration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
