<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-01-01T19:06:22+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Adi’s blog</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Focus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/01/focus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Focus" /><published>2020-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/01/focus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/01/focus.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://alexand.ro/2018/08/how-focus-became-more-valuable-than-intelligence&quot;&gt;This blog post&lt;/a&gt; is a good reminder of the value of attention. I agree with the author that focus is more important than intelligence because it ultimately determines one’s productive output. This theme is echoed by many other sources I’ve come across, e.g. Deep Work by Cal Newport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How you use your time makes all the difference. Everyone has the same 24 hours in a day (approximately - of course there are differences which affect the useful hours we &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; take advantage of), and what we control most is how we spend those hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attention&quot;&gt;Attention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are numerous forces vying for our attention all the time. The value of paying attention to most of these is little, whilst the cost is great. I think there is a Pareto relationship here: 80% of the things that want your attention will contribute 20% toward helping you achieve your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to productivity lies in increasing the proportion of time spent working toward goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some may take issue with this approach, feeling that “goals aren’t everything in life”. A goal simply means a ‘desired result’. When you are hungry, you eat. If you don’t have food, you acquire food, by making or finding it. The goal is to eliminate the hunger, and you act in a way to achieve that desired result. Everything we do is goal driven, whether we realise it or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;intention&quot;&gt;Intention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all goals are created equal. A simple and useful way to categorise goals is by intention: did you &lt;em&gt;choose&lt;/em&gt; this goal? Our behaviour is constantly progressing us toward a result, but is it the desired result of our choosing? When you get sucked in to consuming social media, blogs, or edutainment videos, where are you going to end up? A good sign you didn’t choose the goal is if you don’t know the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to act with intention, to exercise our choice in how we spend our time. That starts with recognising when we are behaving with intention vs inertia. Just like a ball rolls down a hill to the lowest point and requires energy to get back up, we are inclined to go down the path of least resistance, allowing the forces around us to guide our actions. This process left unchecked leads someone to a result that, at best, doesn’t benefit them, and at worst, actively harms them for someone else’s benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By constantly checking your intention, you will become aware of many behaviours that are not ‘in the direction’ of your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;guilty-pleasures&quot;&gt;Guilty Pleasures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awareness is a big deal. Where you were once blind, now you can see. Being aware of the ways in which you spend your time &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; directed toward your goals will help you eliminate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we are all human. There are things we do for passion, desire, to satisfy cravings, and other goals that one would not typically consider having ‘long term value’. This doesn’t mean the behaviours are value-less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a guilty pleasure of mine, for example: watching edutainment videos on Youtube, CuriosityStream, etc. This may be considered a more productive time wasting than social media, but it can be time wasting all the same. What decides whether it is a valuable hobby vs a time sink is the way in which the time is spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gain several benefits from this guilty pleasure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I learn interesting things&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I get food for thought&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I feel a certain way e.g. distracted from my worries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s categorise these as ‘thinking’ and ‘feeling’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thinking&quot;&gt;Thinking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond a point, though, my mental capacity to absorb knowledge is maxed out. Think of a sponge: when wet, it absorbs water until a point after which any more water simply falls off the sponge. Brains are the same - after a certain amount of consumption, there is no more space. For anything new to ‘stick’ something old needs to be ‘overwritten’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, we forget most of what we consume. Effective retention of knowledge requires thought and recall. Videos are notorious for being passive consumption, in which the consumer need do nothing other than exist in front of the medium. Reading is slightly better, as one has to focus on the words on the page, but all consumption has the same rules: if you don’t make an effort to think through and recall what you learned, you will forget it. Even if you make such efforts, you will forget it, but less so. The more such efforts you make, the less you will forget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the goal of consumption is to gain knowledge, then a practice of rigorous thinking and recall must be applied else that goal will be mostly unachieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feeling&quot;&gt;Feeling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another goal of consumption is to feel. All our life experiences affect us emotionally, and we often choose experiences based on our prediction of how they will make us feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you watch an action film, you feel feel energised, respite from your concerns, excitement, awe, etc. When you read a dark book, you feel sorrow, melancholy, fear, anger. In addition to affecting our thinking, these experiences have powerful effects on our feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experiencing the full range of human emotions is vital and very valuable, but again there needs to be balance and intention. If I’m going through a depressive period, feeling energised and motivated is going to benefit me, not feeling sad and lethargic. I already feel sad and lethargic, so I will choose experiences which counteract those. Likewise in happy times, it’s prudent to remind oneself of the problems that still exist, the work still to be done, the ways in which things go wrong. This is not to bring an end to the good times, but rather to give one cause to focus and continue to progress instead of getting lazy and losing momentum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having these intentions in mind enables you to detect when the behaviour is not having the intended effect. For example, if I go to the movies to watch an upbeat and high energy feel good film and walk out not feeling good, what are the chances another film of the same kind will help? Most will agree I should change tracks to something different to achieve my desired emotional state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply that analogy to Youtube: After spending an hour on Youtube, I have certainly maxed out mental capacity to absorb knowledge. I am now only watching to achieve some emotional state. If after an hour I still don’t have that emotional state, something in my approach is not working and I need to change tactics. Perhaps I should go out for a run, do some journalling, call up a friend. But not more Youtube - it’s not going to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;distraction&quot;&gt;Distraction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many things are demanded of humans, and sometimes it’s important to take some time off by being distracted from the responsibilities and concerns we carry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can become a dangerous addiction, with distraction being the goal rather than a tool to be selectively used in achieving our goals. The internet, with its infinite scrolling, autoplay, and endless content is a potent force in enabling this self-destructive behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best mitigation for this is to use distraction as productivity - exercise is likely to be a lot more potent distraction than the internet, and will make you feel much better afterwards, as well as improving your overall health. Do that instead!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;transition&quot;&gt;Transition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transition from unhealthy and undirected behaviours begins with awareness, then selectively replacing chunks of time with more productive or at least more varied behaviours. In this way, you will start spending more time with intent in behaviours of your choosing that will take you toward your goals, or at least benefit you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start&quot;&gt;Start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to make change is getting started. Just showing up makes a big difference. The only metric you need to worry about is how your time is being spent - even a minute you can spend in an intentional way that will improve you is progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;focus&quot;&gt;Focus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are single threaded. Much research has shown that multitasking yields little if no benefit, and we are much more optimised for devoting our undivided attention to one thing at a time. This is the key to productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to tune out all else to the exclusion of the current object of focus is described in many ways: zazen, deep work, flow are but a few names for it. We are able to work most effectively when we are in this state of focus. Those who have experienced it know it’s wonders - the hours fly by and your internal monologue disappears, the mind becomes a calm place and there is little or no distinction between thought and action. It really is a wonderful state of consciousness, and most of not all of my best work as been produced in this state of mind. It’s also a deeply pleasurable state of mind, one always feels a deep sense of satisfaction after such an episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Achieving this state, like anything, takes practice. The most effective way to practice is to focus and eliminate distractions. I think the more time you spend devoting your undivided attention toward one task, the more likely you are to enter a flow state, and the easier it will be for you to do the same for another activity, at another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time is a non-renewable resource. It only depletes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attention is a very limited resource and is constantly demanded by everything around us.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Of the factors that differentiate people, life experiences, and achievements, how you spend your time is the factor over which you have the most control.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where you pay your attention is how you spend your time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everything you do is goal driven. A goal simply means a ‘desired result’.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you don’t choose our own goals, you will work towards someone else’s goals, whether you realise it or not.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working toward your goals requires intention and energy. There are powerful forces inside and outside you that will divert your energy away from your goals if you do not resist their influence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resisting these forces requires focus on your goals and the behaviours that will take you to them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus is achieved by eliminating roadblocks and distractions to enable paying undivided attention to the activity you are engaged in.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus is a skill that only improves through practice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus is more important than intelligence - think of intelligence like a motor and focus like a rudder. Pointed in the wrong direction, a powerful motor will take you very far away from your destination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>adi</name></author><summary type="html">This blog post is a good reminder of the value of attention. I agree with the author that focus is more important than intelligence because it ultimately determines one’s productive output. This theme is echoed by many other sources I’ve come across, e.g. Deep Work by Cal Newport.</summary></entry></feed>